So you have all of these numbers,
strings, and booleans, but
what are you supposed to do with them?
All of this data you've worked with so
far has been for a one time use only.
You define the string, Hello,
it's returned and that's it.
That's the end.
The string Hello is now gone.
&gt;&gt; You need a way to be able to store
data, so that you can use it or
change it later.
To do this, you can use variables.
You've probably heard of variables
before, maybe in a math class.
Let's say you have a variable called X,
and it's assigned the value 5.
And then let's say we have
the expression X + 1.
Since X has a value of 5, we can
substitute the value of 5 in for X.
So the expression becomes 5 + 1 = 6.
&gt;&gt; In JavaScript, variable stored data,
much like how the variable you
just saw stored the value of 5.
And they're not limit to
the storing just numerical values,
you can store any data in two variable.
To create a variable, use the var
keyword followed by the variableName,
and the assignment operator.
The assignment operator
is the equal sign.
And then on the right side
of the assignment operator,
put the value you want to
assign to the variable.
As an example, here's my cat Zoe.
We can use a variable called name and
set it equal to the string Zoe for
her name.
And for her age,
we can create a variable called age, and
set that to the number 4,
since Zoe's 4 years old.
Eventually, when Zoe
has her next birthday,
I'll be able to use the age variable I
created to increment Zoe's age by 1, so
the variable age will return
Zoe's updated age of 5.
Now, Zoe's 5 years old.