As you continue to write more and
more conditional statements,
sometimes you might run into
code that looks like this.
Basically each one of these
conditional statements is checking for
a specific value in one variable, and
if that's true then the code inside
the if statement will be ran.
Just to show you how this works,
let's run this code and
see what its output back to us.
All right, so because the viable option
is set to 3 we get print it back you
selected option 3, so
not terribly complicated.
Now what about told you there's another
way to achieved the same result without
using any conditional statement.
Well, in fact, there's just so
happens to be another way and
that is by using a switch statement.
Now switch statement only works in
situations like these where you have
a bunch of chained if statements based
on the value of the same variable.
Let me rewrite this code
using a switch statement and
then I'll explain how it works.
I'll keep the conditional statement
version here on this side so
you can see the difference.
Okay, so
what I've done is I've wrapped all my
code inside of a switch statement.
And just like it reads,
I want to switch which piece of code
is ran based on the variable option.
The other thing I've done is I have
replaced each if statement with a case
clause where the value of the case
represents the value the variable
option needs to be in order to run the
code that is contained underneath it.
Basically, if the value of option
is say, 3 when our code reaches
the switch statement, it's going to
look to see if a case like that exists.
If it does, and in this case it does,
then it transfers control of that case,
and continues executing.
If it doesn't, then it bypasses
the switch statement completely.
Just to show you how this works,
let's run this code, and
see what is output back to us.
Look at that.
Instead of just printing you selected
option 3 we also got option 4,
option 5 and option 6, so
why is this happening?
Well, it's important to understand
exactly what is going on when you use
a switch statement.
Remember, once our code
reaches a switch statement,
it looks to see if in case for
the bearable we are switching on exist.
If it does, then it transfers control
to that case and continues executing.
But what it doesn't do is prevent any
of the cases below it from not running.
This behavior is called falling through.
You see, you can think of a switch
statement almost like jumping you to
a line of code,
based on the value of a variable.
So in this case, option is set to 3 so
we jump to the case 3, and
then we continue running our code.
That's why the other print
statement get executed.
If you actually want to
stop after a case is ran,
then you will need to
use the keyword break.
A break statement can be used
to exit our switch statement so
that no other cases are ran.
If I add break statements to each
case and then ran this code again,
you see that we only get
back you selected option 3.
Also, technically I don't need the break
statement here on the last case because
this is the last case
in a switch statement.
So there's a couple of things
to take away from this.
Switch statements only work in
situations where you want to execute
statements of code based on
the value of some variable.
It's just another alternative and you
might see it come up from time to time.
Another thing worth mentioning is that
you can use a switch statement on
any type of data, not just numbers.
Also, there are even some
scenarios where you might want to
leverage the falling through
behavior of a switch statement.
We'll look at that more
closely in the next section.