Wow, we covered a lot of material.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, we did.
&gt;&gt; As you continue through
the rest of this course,
remember what you
learned in this lesson.
First, breaking down problems
into their logical steps
is the first sign of a good programmer.
As you face new challenges,
stop to think about how you could break
the problem down into smaller steps.
&gt;&gt; Second,
using conditional statements and
logical operators will be paramount to
your success as a JavaScript programmer.
By telling your code when and
how to run,
you can create algorithms to solve
even the most complex problems.
&gt;&gt; And finally,
remember the advanced techniques you
learned towards the end of this lesson.
Things like truthy and falsy, the
ternary operator, and switch statements
will pop up more often as you begin
to work with more advanced code.
&gt;&gt; That's it for now.
We'll be waiting for
you in the next lesson.