With loops you often need to increase or
decrease the value of a variable
in order to step through the loop.
For instance,
with this loop we're using x = x +
1 to increase the value of x by 1.
Before it starts the next
iteration of the loop.
With JavaScript and
many other programming languages.
There's actually an increment operator.
That gives you a short cut for
doing the exact same thing.
And it is written in two different ways.
You have x++ and you have ++x.
X++ is actually just
the same as x = x + 1.
However, what it is going to do
is return the original value of
x before it increments it.
You can read this as return
x then increments it.
And just to show you what that means and
how that looks.
Let's just do this over in
the JavaScript console.
So if I was to create
a variable called x.
And let's set it = to 0.
If I increment it using the operator.
It returns back 0.
And you're like, what the heck?
I thought it was suppose to go up by 1?
Well, what's actually happening is
that it returns the value back to us.
Then it increments it.
So if we look at the value of x now.
It's 1, so it has been incremented.
It just sort of did it after the fact.
Now, ++x is going to work the same way.
It's going to increment by 1.
But it's going to do it and
then return the value back to us.
So if we run ++x.
It returns back 2.
It's incremented it.
It's still 2 after that.
So it just sort of does it beforehand.
And that's the difference
between the two.
Now you might be wondering,
when should you use one over the other?
In many cases it doesn't really matter
which one you're going to choose.
When we're talking about loops.
They both increment x by 1.
However the value it returns might be
important depending on the program that
you're writing.
So it's just something to keep in mind.
Another thing you might be wondering is,
are there other shorthand
ways of doing arithmetic?
Can I increase something by two?
Can I decrease something?
Can I do like quick multiplication?
And in fact there is.
So I'm just going to show you a couple
of different examples of that.
So let's create a new variable called y.
And we'll set it equal to 5.
And let's say we want
to subtract y by 1.
We could do y = y- 1.
And that's going to give us 4.
That's going to do what we want.
But we can also write y-- which
is the decrement operator.
And it's going to do the same thing for
us.
So, do y--.
Again, this one behaves similar to ++.
It's going to return the value back,
then decrement it.
So we look at the value of y.
It's now 3.
We could also do something like --y.
Again similar to the increment operator.
The decrement operator
works the same way.
Now a couple other shorthand things you
can do are multiplication and division.
So let's create a new variable
called z and set it equal to 10.
So if we want to multiply 10 by,
let's say, 8.
We could say z *= 8.
What that's going to do is it's
going to multiply the value of z by 8.
And then reassign it back to z.
If we do that, z is now 80.
And we could also do the same thing for
division.
We might say, divide it by, let's say 4.
And that's going to give us 20.
So, yeah, there are a lot of
shorthand ways for doing arithmetic.
They're going to come in handy as
you continue to write longer and
longer programs.
And practice using them in your loops.
So, instead of writing x = x + 1,
we can do x++.