Let's take a moment to talk about scope.
Apart from regular syntax errors, scope
will be at the heart of many coding bugs
you run into in pretty much
any programming language.
When programmers talk about scope,
they're talking about the part of the
program where a particular identifier,
such as a variable or a function name,
is visible or accessible.
Trying to figure out if something
is in scope can be tricky at first.
So let's start with an analogy.
&gt;&gt; Hey.
&gt;&gt; Do you know where I can find
the book Great Expectations?
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that's in the classic
literature section, come follow me.
&gt;&gt; Perfect.
&gt;&gt; In the example you just saw,
James was able to get information about
the book he wanted because he asked for
the book while he was in the library.
You could say that the information
about where the book was is in scope.
&gt;&gt; Hey, I'm looking for
this book, Great Expectations.
Do you know where I could find it?
&gt;&gt; Yeah,
I mean the library is right here.
[MUSIC]
I don't know why you're asking me.
&gt;&gt; Right, yeah, makes a lot of sense.
[MUSIC]
&gt;&gt; In the second example,
when James was outside the library,
the information he wanted and
where he was requesting the information
from, was no longer in the same scope.
So he couldn't find the book, and
he couldn't really ask anyone to give
him information about how to find it.