Developer tools allow you to debug and
test out your ideas
directly in the browser.
If you're familiar with HTML or CSS,
you may have used developer tools to
experiment with the style of a webpage.
But you can also use it with JavaScript.
&gt;&gt; Developer tools are often
used as a sandbox.
In other words,
a place to mess around with any code
without any long-term consequences.
You can use developer tools to
debug problem you run in to or
to test a piece of code
you've just learned.
If you open any website
that uses JavaScript,
the console will tell you if there any
warnings or errors on the page and
will also display any output,
print it with console.log.
&gt;&gt; Note that anytime you're using
the console on these course,
you might see some errors or
warnings from the site you're visiting.
That's okay, this is very common and
will not affect the code that
you right in these course.