Scope can be a tricky subject,
especially when you're bouncing
between global and function scope.
One of the gotchas scope can result
in is called scope overriding, or
shadowing.
To show you how this works and
how you can avoid it, let's take
a look at the following code example.
Here we have the same variable
bookTitle being assigned values
in two different scopes.
The bookTitle in the global scope is
assigned the value Le Petit Prince, and
the book title in this function scope is
assigned the value The Little Prince.
If we print out the value of bookTitle
at each part of this program you'll see
that in the final console.log statement
that The Little Prince is printed out.
However, at this point in the code
we're no longer in the function scope
of the displayBookEnglish function.
So why is the book title Le Petit Prince
not being printed instead?
Well, this is a classic case of
scope overriding or shadowing.
When we reach the fifth line of
this code the book title variable
from the global scope is actually
being reassigned with the value
The Little Prince.
So the book title here is being
reassigned by the book title here.
That means when we finally reach
the last console.log in this code,
bookTitle in the global
scope has been changed
even though we exited
the function scope.
To prevent this from happening, we are
going to simply declare a new variable
inside the displayBookEnglish function.
So instead of reassigning bookTitle,
we're going to create
a different variable.
So now we've got a variable
inside displayBookEnglish that is
relative at this function scope.
And our bookTitle that's declared in
the global scope will remain unchanged.
And that way, when we reach the tenth
line in our code and we print it out for
the third time, it's going to print
out what we expect, Le Petit Prince.