So as you can tell we've got a lot of
donuts that we've gotta keep up with at
our shop.
And trying to organize all
them is going to be a problem.
We could create individual variables
to keep track of each donut, but
that's going to mean multiple variables,
not so
great variable names, and
just a whole lot of mess.
It's not exactly the best solution.
Instead, to make this easier, we can
use a data structure called an Array.
An array is a data structure that we
can use to store multiple values.
Also, one thing that makes
arrays really awesome
is that the values we store
in an array are ordered.
You can almost think of
an array like a numbered list,
where each item in
the list has a number.
And we can use that number to refer
back to the item when we need it,
with the one big difference being that
arrays will start at 0 instead of
starting at 1, but we'll look
at that more in just a second.
An array should work perfectly for
organizing all of our donuts,
so let's create one.
All right, so
here I've got all of our donuts, but
they're represented as
individual variables.
So we need to fix that,
if we're going to create an array
to hold all of our donuts.
So the first thing I'm going to do is
I'm just going to select all of these
variables and we're doing
a little keyboard shortcut magic,
I'll get rid of these semicolons,
I'm going to jump to the front.
Get rid of these variable
declarations and the equals sign.
So we're left with just the strings.
Okay, perfect.
So that's number one.
The next step is we need to
create a variable that can
hold all these strings and
it's going to be our donuts array.
So to do that, I'm going to move
those down a few spaces and
I'm going to say var donuts = {};,
so the opening and the closing
brackets represent an empty array.
At this point,
we've got an array, it's empty.
It doesn't have anything in it, but when
we put the opening bracket, it says,
hey this variable's an array.
And then the closing bracket's
going to show the end of the array,
so that's how we know
that it's an array.
Now for the last step, what I'm
going to do is I'm going to take all
these strings and
put them into an array.
Now, the one thing that you need to make
sure that you do when creating an array,
is that you separate each element
in the array with a comma.
Now to do that, I'm going to use some
more keyboard shortcuts here and
I'm going to select all of our lines and
I'm going to put a comma at the end.
Another thing that I'm going to do is
I'm going to get rid of that last comma.
Because chocolate donut
holes is our last element,
we don't need that
extra comma on the end.
All right, and we'll do one more thing,
we'll get rid of all of this space,
okay.
And let's just cut this and
move it in to our donuts array.
All right and that's it.