There are lots of ways to loop
over arrays in JavaScript, and
each way has its pros and cons.
For loops are very versatile and
give you complete control
over the looping process.
You can explicitly define
where to start and
stop in the array, whether you want
to skip over values in the array, and
even whether you'd like to break out of
the loop early using a break statement.
When in doubt, you could
probably use a for loop to do it.
.forEach gives you a concise
way of looping over an array
if you know you're going to be looping
over every element from start to finish.
You have less versatility than
you do with a regular for
loop, but you can access each
element directly, which is nice.
And you don't need an index
of an element to do that.
Map is one more array method you'll
want in your JavaScript tool belt.
Similar to for each,
you can define a call back function
that performs an operation on
each element in the array.
The difference here is,
map returns a new array with the new
values your function calculated.
So, there you have it.
There are tons of ways to
iterate over a data in an array.
And you can check out even more of them
by reading the Mozilla documentation.
But for now,
you got three you can pull from,
depending on what you
need to accomplish.
For loops, forEach and
now map, if you need to create
a new array using your function.