Welcome back.
You've made it to the last
lesson of this course.
And now it's finally time
to talk about objects.
&gt;&gt; Objects are an incredibly
powerful feature of JavaScript.
They allow us to wrap up
pieces of related data and
functionality, into
one single container.
If you remember back to our
previous lesson on arrays,
arrays are a special kind
of object in JavaScript.
Arrays have properties like length and
methods like reverse, sort, push, and
pop.
That make them useful for
working with structured organized data.
&gt;&gt; But
objects are not just limited to arrays.
JavaScript comes with a whole set
of other useful built-in objects.
Plus, you can even
create your own objects.
For example, throughout this course,
you're seeing code about Facebook
profiles, bank accounts, cats, crew
members, a donut shop, and so much more.
Each of these things had data
associated with them and
functions that we used to manipulate or
operate on that data.
With objects, we can take this
a step further by organizing or
encapsulating all of the data and
functionality associated with
a particular thing inside an object.
&gt;&gt; For example,
take this umbrella [SOUND].
I really like umbrellas.
And we could create this umbrella
as an object in JavaScript.
In fact, we could take almost
any real world object and
represent it as a JavaScript object.
&gt;&gt; Let's take a look at how we
might write code to represent
Julia's umbrella.