As you start creating objects, there
are some naming conventions that you'll
want to follow when
defining object properties.
Not following these conventions
can lead to some sneaky bugs.
So I want to spend some time showing you
some things that you'll want to avoid as
well as best practices for
naming object properties.
Okay, so
here I have a couple of examples and
let's just walk through through
each one of these one by one.
In the first example I've got
an object called person, and
it's got some properties that
are used to describe the person.
Actually this person is my dad [LAUGH].
So his name's John, he's 55,
and he's got three children.
Myself, my twin brother Jarrod,
and my sister Alexis.
So anyways, there's two things
I want to point out here.
First, I'm using quotes
around the property names.
Now quotes are perfectly valid but
they're not required.
However, sometimes when you use
quotes around property names
it can mass some potential problems.
For example, I'm going to copy this
code over to our console and let's try
accessing some of these properties so
I can show you what I mean.
So we'll copy this and
paste it over here.
So I've got my person object copied over
to the console and let's give it a go.
Remember we've got two different
ways to access properties.
We can use bracket notation or
dot notation.
So let's just start with
bracket notation first.
So let me try person and let's try
to get the name of this person.
To do that it turns back John.
Okay, so that works.
That's not a problem.
And let's try doing one of the children,
the first child which is me.
And awesome so it tuns back James.
But now let's trying doing
it with dot notation and
this is where you're
going to see the problem.
So we do dot name, no that's still okay.
But what about first child?
Uh-oh, we've got a syntax error.
It doesn't seem to like our
1stChild using dot notation.
So, this is, basically,
the second thing I want to point out.
Don't use numbers as the first
character in your property names.
Technically, it works,
if you're using bracket notation, but
it's going to limit you when
you're using dot notation and
it's just bad practice in general,
so avoid it.
And just to show you what I mean by
quotes sometimes masking potential
problems, if we drop the quotes which
I've done now in this example, and
we copy and
paste it back over to the console,
we're going to get an error back.
So yes, so sometimes quotes
can mask potential problems
when you're naming object properties.
So the moral here is
that don't use numbers to
start your object property names.
And really for this example, for
first, second and third child.
To do this right we should just
change this over to being an array
that holds the children.
Yeah, that's a lot better.
All right, so
let's move on to this next example.
Based on the first example you might
already see where the problems
are going to be.
But let me go ahead and
point them out anyway.
So again, we're using quotes for
property names and
it's going to let us get away with
some things that normally don't fly.
The first is using spaces, and
the second is using hyphens.
You should definitely avoid
doing either of these things for
the same reasons as using
a number as the first character.
Neither of these will work
when you use dot notation.
So if we copy this over to
the JavaScript console and
give it a try we'll see what I mean.
So we'll say garage.fire truck, and
yeah so there is a syntax error here.
And then the same thing goes for
our hyphen, if we say race-car,
again another syntax error.
Now the reason I've got this
is a different example,
is because both of these properties are
examples of multi-word property names.
If you want to use multi-word
properties Instead of using a space or
a hyphen the preferred method
is using camel casing.
Now camel casing is pretty simple.
You just remove the spaces
between multiple words, so
we'll do that here, or
in this case a hyphen.
And then you want to upper case the
first letter in the rest of the words
throughout the property name.
So to recap property names can
be any combination of upper and
lower case letters as well as numbers
just as long as numbers aren't
the beginning of your property name.
Like you can put a number
anywhere in here and
that's going to be fine,
just not at the beginning.
Also using camel casing for
multi-word properties is going to be
better than using spaces or hyphens.
Again, you can use spaces or
hyphens when you're using quotes
around your property names.
But then it's going to break on you
when you try to use dot notation
to access those properties.
So rather than doing that,
just avoid that completely and
use camel casing that's
going to be your best bet.
Finally, one other thing worth
mentioning is all of these rules
also apply to just
normal variable names.
So if your variable name is good,
then it is probably also good for
a property name.